亲爱的
Hey, sweetie.
真是抱歉
Yeah, I'm sorry.
会议时间比预想的长一些
No, the meeting's running a little late.
你也知道马西森那个人
Well, you know Matheson--
就喜欢听自己讲话
The guy loves to hear himself talk.
好的  我们餐馆见
Yeah. Yeah. I'll meet you at the restaurant.
我们正在研究合同内容
Hey, we're going over the contracts now.
我得挂了
I gotta get back in there.
我也爱你
I love you too.
付你工钱是要你来打扫
You're getting paid to clean,
不是让你逛商场的  韦斯奇
not window shop, Vesky.
你说我是贼吗
You calling me a thief?
放松点  不就开个玩笑嘛
Take it easy. Just yanking your chain.
该死的  这里冷死了
Damn, it's freezin' in here.
再冷也比满屋子的血腥味强
Better the cold than the smell.
之前总以为我的工作够糟的了
Used to think my job sucked.
-你一小时赚多少  -不够多
- How much you make an hour anyway?  - Not enough.
问题是这份工作
The difference is that this job
只是我的权宜之计
is just a temporary setback.
而你  将永远是个二货
You, on the other hand, will always be a schmuck.
当个有养老金和各种福利待遇的二货
Yeah. Schmuck with a guaranteed pension and benefits.
我照单全收
I'll take it.
抱歉我迟到了
I'm sorry I'm late.
今晚可不准谈论房地产了
No talking about real estate tonight.
我真心希望你能让自己放松一下
I really want you to just enjoy yourself.
看到你穿上这条裙子
Well, seeing you in that dress,
我就心满意足了
I'd say mission accomplished.
等你看到裙子里面是什么
Gets a little better.
会更满足的
Wait till you see what's on underneath.
柠檬鲜活八爪鱼  请慢用
Fresh tako with lemon. Enjoy.
我点了这道特别的开胃菜
I...ordered the appetizer special.
我以为八爪鱼是一种金枪鱼
Oh, I thought tako was a kind of tuna.
这东西怎么能吃
Ooh. We're so not eating this.
至少试一下吧
Well, we should at least try it.
拜托  伯特  它还在动呢
Please, it's moving, Bert.
太恶心了
Oh, it's so gross!
实际上  没那么恶心
Actually, it's... not that bad.
真的吗  我可不吃这个
Really? I'm not eating it.
为我们
To us...
结婚三周年  干杯
On our third anniversary.
我初识你的那天
The day I met you was--
那天
Was--
伯特
Bert?
伯特  怎么了
Bert. What is it? What--
亲爱的  你怎么了
Honey, what's wrong?
来人啊  叫救护车
Someone, please call 911!
亲爱的
Honey.
Honey...
豪斯
House.
我猜你是因为慈善晚会而躲我的吧
I assume you're avoiding me because of the charity gala.
是这周五吗
This Friday?
我彻底给忘了
It's completely slipped my mind.
-你会去吧  -我的意思是
- So you'll be there?  - No, I meant
我忘了告诉你我不去了
it slipped my mind to tell you I'm not going.
如果我拿了奖  你却没出席
What do you think it'll look like
别人会怎么看
if you don't show up when I get an award?
他们会觉得我对得奖和慈善不屑一顾
Like I don't give a crap about awards, charities,
就这样
what it looks like.
你有没有想要
If you ever want--
两天前我就应邀了
I RSVPed two days ago.
怎么  在你眼里我就那么混蛋吗
What, you think I'm a complete ass?
如果你早就决定要去  你为什么
If you were already going, why did you--
前戏
Foreplay.
怎么了
What?
你系的是我的领带吗
Are you wearing my tie?
我在你的衣柜里看到的
Oh, I saw it in your closet,
正好跟我的衬衫很搭
and it happened to match my shirt.
你到我的衣柜里去干什么
Why were you in my closet?
找领带啊  有什么大不了的
Looking for a tie. What's the big deal?
显然  出于某种原因他希望你"出柜"
Obviously, he wants you out of the closet for some reason.
我猜是婚姻  对此我还是挺开明的
I suspect marriage, but I'm liberal that way.
告诉我  一个人的所有已知过敏源测试
Now, tell me how someone can have an allergic reaction
都呈阴性  他为什么还会有过敏反应
when all their tests were negative for known allergens.
环境因素
Environmental.
档案上写着  他是房地产开发商
File says he's a real estate developer.
可能是在参观建筑工地时
Could have been exposed to something
接触到了某种物质
visiting a construction site.
他在说谎
He's lying.
他并非行政人员  我看过他的手
He's not an executive. I saw his hands.
上面都是茧和小切口
They're covered with calluses and little cuts.
他靠双手做苦力  经常性的
He works with them. A lot.
起立
Stand up.
我们的小丫头  终于长大了
Our little girl... is finally growing up.
我们一直梦想着这一天
I mean, you dream of this day,
但当这一天终于来临的时候
but when it finally happens...
你拆穿他时
So what did Mr. Meat Hooks say
勾拳先生说什么了
when you called him a liar?
我没拆穿他
I didn't.
一步一个脚印
Hmm. Baby steps.
快去继续你的学步之旅吧
Go down there and do it.
可如果我弄错了呢
But what if I'm wrong?
那就是冒犯他了
I'll just end up offending him.
把那个当作意外收获吧
Consider that part a bonus.
好吧  我派一个兄长去帮你
All right, I'll send along one of your big brothers to help.
你想要大黑脸  马屁精还是小矮人
You want scary, smarmy, or shorty?
我们需要问你些问题
We need to ask you a few questions.
如果你不介意的话  能否和他单独谈谈
Alone. If you don't mind.
问题会涉及到个人隐私
Uh, they tend to be personal in nature.
我是他妻子
I'm his wife.
也许比他回答地更清楚
I can probably answer them better than he can.
是关于他工作的事
They're about his job.
跟工作有什么关系
Well, what does that matter?
他整天坐在办公室里
He sits in an office all day--
亲爱的  你就休息一下  没关系
Honey, take a break. It's okay.
不  说真的  如果他真的有事
No! Seriously, if there's something really wrong with him,
我想知道是怎么回事
I-I wanna know about it.
不是这样的
It's not.
我们想问问他工作时吃进去什么午饭
Our questions are about what he eats for lunch at work
又排出什么物体
and what comes out at the end--
主要是排泄物
Bowel movements, mostly.
颜色  质地  味道
Color, texture. Smell.
好吧
Oka--
你肯定帮不上什么忙了
Pretty sure you can't help with that.
我还是出去透透气吧
Maybe I could use a break.
谢谢你这么诚实
Thank you for your honesty.
不客气
You're welcome.
我不能让我妻子知道这些
I can't let my wife find out about this.
你们得答应替我保密
You have to promise me.
那要看情况是否
That depends on if it's considered--
我们保证
We promise.
因为经济危机  我失去了一切
I lost everything because of the recession,
失去了整个房地产公司
my entire real estate company.
她对此一无所知
And she has no idea.
那你现在以何为生
So what do you do for a living now?
在大学时我做过清洁工
I used to be a janitor when I was in college,
现在我快四十的人了
and now I'm almost 40
先前为别人盖房子  现在为他们清房子
and doing it for the people I built homes for.
为什么
Why?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我需要钱啊
'Cause I need the money.
不  我是说为什么要向你妻子隐瞒这事
No, I mean why lie to your wife about it?
这不关我们的事  真的
Oh, n-none of our business, really.
哪种清洁呢
What kind of cleaning?
工业清洁
Industrial jobs.
犯罪现场清理
Crime scene cleanup.
修补化粪池  除霉
Septic tank repair. Mold removal.
真是慢性自杀
It's physically killing me.
腐蚀性化学清洁剂  未经处理的污水
It's the holy grail of potential diseases--
霉菌孢子和真菌感染
caustic cleaning chemicals, raw sewage,
简直是各种可能疾病的天堂
mold spores, fungal infections.
更别说他昨天还在凶案现场
And not to mention cleaning up blood
清理血液和其他体液了
and other bodily fluids from a homicide yesterday.
我们应该去检查下犯罪现场
We should check out the crime scene.
他有可能从受害者的血液中
He might have picked up a bacterial infection
感染了某种细菌
from the victim's blood.
患者已经把那清理干净并消毒了
Place has been cleaned and sanitized by our patient.
我们申请了验尸报告
We sent for the autopsy report--
大概一周后才能拿到
probably take a week to get it.
他不工作的时候
When he's not working,
每天都在哪里躲着呢
where does he go all day to hide out?
原来的房地产办公室
His old real estate office?
治疗细菌感染  同时
Treat for bacterial infection. Meantime...
伯特带上厄尼去他办公室检查环境毒素
Bert take Ernie and check his office for environmentals.
我去跟卡迪说快点弄来验尸报告
I'll talk to Cuddy about getting the autopsy results faster.
你是伯特
You're Bert.
他是厄尼
He's Ernie.
他们还真是室友  精辟
And they're both roommates. That was a good one.
好在202房的那个病人患有老年痴呆
At least the alzheimer's patient in Room 202
不会记得她的火腿三明治只剩一半
won't remember she only got half a ham sandwich.
我是在帮她的忙
I'm doing her a favor.
你真的要出席慈善晚会吗
You're really going to the charity gala?
有何居心
Why?
我想讨好我女朋友
I wanna do something nice for my girlfriend.
你才不会呢  除非对你有利
You never do anything unless it stands to benefit you.
我意识到三次失败的婚姻
I realize that three failed marriages
能够让一个男人内心扭曲尖酸刻薄
can leave a man twisted and bitter inside,
但是在一段稳定的感情中
but in a good relationship,
人们通常会为彼此付出
people sometimes do things for each other.
一百美元赌你不会出席
A hundred says you don't show up.
你这是在激我出席吗
You're giving me an incentive to actually show up?
为你自己激我吗
A personal, selfish incentive?
我就是赚点小钱
I'm just making easy money.
两百美元
200.
卡迪设的上限是多少
How high did Cuddy authorize you to go?
她  她没有
She--she didn't--
三百美元
300.
她真的希望你能出席
She really wants you there.
为何
Why do people believe
没人相信我能行善啊
I'm incapable of doing anything nice?
吃一堑长一智
Experience.
不就是条领带嘛
It's a tie.
我又没穿你内裤
I'm not wearing your underwear.
都跟你道歉了  你想要回去吗
I said I was sorry. You want the tie back?
能开始工作了吗
Can we get to work?
我不知道你这是冷暴力
I can't tell if you're being passive-aggressive
还是你平时就这熊样作乐
or this is just your regular fun-loving personality.
都是  领带你留着吧
Both. And you can keep the tie.
五年前就过时了
Went out of style five years ago.
维科丁
Vicodin.
他还没有处方
And he doesn't have a prescription.
我们没有测试他是否对麻醉药过敏
We didn't test for an allergic reaction to narcotics.
或者是更显而易见的原因
Or it's the obvious.
看看这个
Take a look at this.
我们认为你是硼酸灼伤
We think you're suffering from boric acid exposure.
疹子正是由此引起的
Which is causing the rash.
我们需要对你的皮肤进行清洗
We need to decontaminate your skin
但愿你还没把硼酸吸进肺里
and hope you didn't inhale it into your lungs.
我感觉我
I-I feel like I'm--
从没见过烧得这么快的
Never seen a fever spike this fast before.
硼酸灼伤的只是表面  不应该导致发烧
Acid exposure burns literally. It shouldn't be causing this.
他怎么了
What's happening to him?
伯特  亲爱的  你还好吗
Bert? Honey, are you all right?
我们得立刻让他退烧
We have to get his fever down right now.
如果体温再升高
If it gets any higher,
就可能导致永久脑损伤
it could cause permanent brain damage.
我们用冷却毯把他的体温降下来了
We used cooling blankets to get his temperature down.
稳定在39度
He stabilized at 102.
不是硼酸的问题
Problem's not boric acid.
我们没在他的皮肤上发现灼伤痕迹
We found no traces of it on his skin.
谋杀案死者的血液感染
Infection from the murder victim's blood?
尸检报告没有发现传染病
Autopsy report was negative for communicable disease.
死者是被女友刺伤致死
Cause of death was an overly stabby girlfriend.
我们在他办公室里发现了维科丁
We found vicodin in his office.
给我
Give it to me.
看着像维科丁的也有可能不是
Might look like vicodin but be something else.
是它没错
It's real.
很遗憾
Unfortunately...
维科丁不会引起皮疹  发烧和关节痛
his vicodin doesn't cause rash, fever, and joint pain.
不过确实能让陶博显得不那么烦人了
Does make Taub considerably less annoying, though.
也许我们想得太复杂了
Maybe we're thinking too far outside the box here.
他的工作有可能暗含着
Just because he could have picked up
一百种外来病  这就代表
any one of a hundred exotic diseases from his job
他很难幸免于难
doesn't mean he didn't.
陶博的生活伴侣说的有理
Taub's life partner has a point.
最初的抗生素治疗反而使他的病情更糟了
Started treatment with antibiotics, and he got worse.
最简单的答案就是以M开头Mia结尾的病
Simple answer begins with "M" Ends with "Mia."
脑膜炎球菌血症
Meningococcemia?
这也成
That works too.
做腰椎穿刺进行确诊
Confirm with a lumbar puncture.
万一我们错了
And on the off chance we're wrong,
找找除了工作和滥用药物外
find out what else he's been lying about
他还撒了什么谎
besides his job and his drug use.
你瞒了你老婆不少事情啊
You sure do hide a lot from your wife.
你的工作  滥用药物  还有什么吗
Your job, your drug use. What else?
那有什么关系
What does it matter?
除非你跟我们实话实说否则我们没法帮你
Can't help you unless you're completely honest with us.
我一直从事体力劳动
I was doing manual labor.
如果我疲惫不堪得回到家
If I came home barely able to move,
黛安会看出端倪的
Diane would know something's up.
为了隐藏疼痛  我才服用维科丁
That's why I take the vicodin-- to hide the pain.
我不是瘾君子
I'm not an addict.
你只隐瞒了这些吗
Is that all you're hiding?
我不止丢了工作
I didn't just lose my job.
这是导火索
Well, that's how it started,
我本以为失业只是一两个月的事
but I figured it'd just last a couple months.
我就刷爆了我们的信用卡
I maxed out our credit cards,
还把我们的屋子做了双重抵押
took a double mortgage on the house,
变卖了所有的投资
and I sold all of our investments.
谁能想到经济危机
Who'd have thought the recession
会持续这么久  是吧
would last this long, huh?
所以你对你老婆撒谎都是奥巴马的错了
So it's Obama's fault you're lying to your wife?
听着...是我搞砸了
Look...I screwed up.
现在为时已晚了
It's too late now.
请你向左侧翻身
I want you to roll over on your left side
你就没在一段感情中
Haven't you ever done something
做过什么后悔的事希望能重新来过的吗
in a relationship you wish you could take back?
也许有
Maybe.
你怎么处理的
How'd you handle it?
实话实说
I told the truth.
在最后关头
Eventually.
那结果如何
How'd that work out?
不怎么样
Not well.
我要为周五晚上的慈善晚会打听点情报
I need some intel on this charity event on friday night.
如果我去了是不是就得捐钱给慈善协会
If I go, do I have to actually give money to charity?
我会去的
I'm going.
只是不想去郁闷
Just don't want it to suck.
应该有办法能让晚会变得有趣些
There has to be a way to make this fun.
出席  乖乖待着  问题解决了
Show up and behave. Problem solved.
你的问题解决了而已
Your problem solved.
你不认为她掌管这破地方十五年
Don't you think she deserves more
应该获得比一块牌匾或些许掌声
than a plaque and a round of applause
更有价值的东西吗
for 15 years of running this dump?
奖品是块表  不是牌匾
It's a watch, not a plaque.
都是陈词滥调
It's a cliche.
我想让晚宴更刺激些
I want to make things more exciting,
安排些能让她铭记终身的事
something she'll remember for more than ten minutes.
好吧  你说的有趣和刺激
Okay. By fun and exciting,
就是指把这事搞砸
You mean screwing this up for cuddy
这样卡迪就不会再妄想让你去类似场合了
so she won't even dream of asking you to go to one again.
你真是见不得我高兴  是吧
You really can't stand seeing me happy, can you?
第一份脑脊液标本的革兰氏染色成阴性
Gram stains are negative in the first csf samples.
这个枪毙  还有三个
One down, three to go.
我饿死了  你想去吃点...
I'm starving. You wanna get a bite after--
-已经有计划了  -约会吗
- Already have plans. - Date?
有什么区别吗
What difference does it make?
我们是室友  不是夫妻
We're roommates, not a married couple.
我们不用每天晚上都一起吃饭
We don't have to eat every night together.
那你的意思是  确实有约会
So you're saying... it's a date?
没错  就是约会
Yeah, it's a date.
我没安排
I don't have plans.
太令人震惊了
Ooh. Shocking.
你是因为我选了你而生气吗
Are you mad because I picked you?
就因为你在干你本该干的活吗
You're stuck actually doing your job?
和病人打打太极对医学院学生无害
A little hazing never hurt a med student.
但我认为这也  毫无益处
I doubt it ever... helped either.
很抱歉我认为
I'm sorry that I think
病人不应该对他妻子撒谎
our patient shouldn't be lying to his wife.
我是女人
I'm a woman.
我猜你我的视角不同
I guess I just have a different perspective.
你是在和我们分享
You're sharing this unique insight
女性不喜欢撒谎这个独特的观点吗
that women don't like lying?
不  我的独特观点是说
Uh, no, I'm sharing my unique insight
你不尊重女性
that you don't respect women.
你每隔几天就和不同的女人睡觉
You sleep with a different one every few days.
或者  你就喜欢这种毫无意义的交往
Or maybe... you find meaning in meaningless relationships.
至少我还有对象
At least I have relationships.
这份脑脊液样品的淋巴细胞数偏高
I'm seeing a high lymphocyte count in the csf sample.
你就不能等到
And that couldn't wait
他们嘲笑完对方之后再说吗
until they finished mocking each other?
这意味着不是脑膜炎球菌血症
That means it's not meningococcemia.
他更糟了  他的腿几乎不能动了
He's getting worse! He can barely move his legs.
我感觉不到了  我感觉不到我的脚了
I can't feel them. I can't feel my feet.
那是什么
What is it?
他怎么了
What is happening to him?
很幸运他的脚保住了
Luckily, he didn't lose his feet.
我们在严重损伤发生前
We were able to restore his circulation
恢复了脚部血液循环
before any serious damage set in.
不是脑膜炎球菌血症  脑脊液中没找到细菌
It's not meningococcemia. Csf was negative for bacteria.
但是淋巴细胞数很高
But high on lymphocytes.
应该是某种病毒感染
It's some kind of viral infection.
血清病符合一切症状
Serum sickness fits everything.
那要有感染源才行
There'd have to be a cause,
可能是某些他用过的药物
some drug he's been exposed to.
在一些罕见病历中  壁虱或蜘蛛咬伤
In rare cases, a tick or a spider bite
-也可能引起  -举手示意
- could set it off-- - Show of hands.
谁会去参加周五晚上的慈善晚会
Who's going to this charity thing Friday night?
我已经有女伴了
Already got a date.
卡迪到时会被嘉奖
Cuddy is getting an award.
我觉得我们都该去  以示支持
I think we should all be there, show our support.
我猜你在计划把它搞砸
I assume you're planning on screwing it up,
因此你想要更多的见证者
so you want to maximize witnesses.
为什么每个人都这么想
Why does everyone go to that?
吃一堑长一智
Experience?
闭嘴
Shut up!
参加宴会  整个周末看门诊你们选哪个
How 'bout go...or work the clinic all weekend?
我听说本月是生殖器疱疹患者觉醒之月
I hear it's genital herpes awareness month.
血清病符合
Serum sickness fits.
停止使用抗生素  开始用皮质激素
Take him off the antibiotics. Start him on corticosteroids.
如果我们是对的  他明早就会好转
If we're right, he'll be better by morning.
约会取消了  对吧
Canceled date, huh?
你窃听了我的电话吗
You're bugging my cell phone?
没  我只是注意到你没穿那件衣服
No. I just noticed you're not wearing it.
什么衣服
What?
你的初次约会衬衫
Your first-date shirt.
-你窥探我所有衣服吗  -我只是善于观察
- You tracking my wardrobe? - I'm just observant.
因此我才能胜任这份工作
That's why I'm good at my job.
这也是为什么
It's also the reason
你开始烦到我有点毛了
you're starting to annoy the crap out of me.
请原谅  我只是想和我的室友
Forgive me for trying to connect a little
交交心
with my roommate.
我刚发现瑞秋现在
I just found out that Rachel is now
与她那网友已经正式地
officially more than just emotional
超越了感情关系
with her online friend.
你已经离婚了  还想怎样
You're getting divorced. What did you expect?
我明白  你说的对
I know. You're right.
只是  一想到这
Just...thinking about it
我就想吐
kinda makes me wanna throw up.
你还想去吃点什么吗
You still wanna get something to eat?
我能做饭
I could cook.
那下可够伤的
Ooh. That had to hurt.
没你那下糟  你刚错过了免费升级
Not as bad as you. You just missed a free upgrade.
又一次  你跑过了充电点
Ha. Just did it again. You ran past the power up.
真见鬼了
Double damn!
你是在让着我吗
Are you just letting me win?
我当然没有让
Of course I'm not letting you--
好吧  就一点
Okay, maybe a little.
-你玩得很爽  对吧  -现在不爽了
- You're having fun, right? - Not anymore.
我以前认为你那种沉闷的状态
I used to think the whole brooding thing
只是你的工作作风
was just part of your work persona,
不过现在我和你住一起了
but now I live with you.
你需要放松  伯特
You need to lighten up, Bert.
用你来教我吗
And you think I need you to show me what?
怎么玩得开心  怎么放松心情吗
How to have fun, relax?
在你抽风之前  我的计谋还好使得很
It was working till you flipped out.
就算我需要学习如何生活
If I was gonna take advice on how to live my life,
老师也不会是你
it would not be from you.
你破产了  毁了你的婚姻
You're broke, you ruined your marriage,
而你还表现得像个受害者
and yet you act like you're the victim here,
好像我们就应该同情你似的
like somehow we're all supposed to feel sorry for you.
是你搞砸了你的人生
You screwed up your life,
而不是什么你老婆在网上遇到的知心朋友
not some emotional friend your wife met on the-- ah!
-怎么了  -我的胃  你...
- What's wrong? - My stomach. You--
你给我下毒了
You poisoned me!
我和你吃了一样的东西
I ate the same thing you did.
我怎么没...
How come I'm not--
额滴神啊
Oh, dear god.
开门  伯特  求你了
Open the door, Bert, please.
宝贝  你说话啊
Baby, talk to me.
他把自己锁在里面  他疯了
He locked himself inside. He went crazy.
他还打了我
He hit me.
伯特
Bert.
快开门  伯特
Open the door, bert.
伯特
Bert?
说话啊
Talk to us.
-伯特.  -快开门
- Bert.  - Open the door.
我出不去  为什么
I can't get out!  Why?
我出不去了
I can't get out!
上帝啊  不
Oh, lord, oh, no!
为什么我...  出不去
Why can't I...get out?
皮疹消失了
Skin rash is gone.
但不管是什么
But whatever it is,
很显然已经波及到他的大脑了
it obviously moved into his brain.
不一定
Or not.
他刚发作了一次精神崩溃
He had a psychotic break.
要我说这通常说明有神经性的疾病
I'd say that usually indicates neurological involvement.
通常  又不是一定
Usually. Not always.
在我们给他用类固醇
The hallucinations stopped
清理系统的时候他的幻觉就停止了
once the steroids we gave him cleared his system.
我认为
I think that--
我认为是我们引起的
I think we caused this.
你怎么了
What happened to you?
陶博昨晚想杀我
Taub tried to kill me last night.
类固醇可能确实清除了皮疹
The steroids probably did clear up the rash,
但其他症状还是没有好转
but the rest of his symptoms are the same.
而且现在两只眼睛都有了结膜炎
And now bilateral conjunctivitis.
抱歉  我去去就来
Uh, excuse me. I'll be back.
我  我得去看看他
I... I, uh, better go check on him.
关节肿大  白细胞数量增多  高烧
Swollen joints, high white count, fever.
结膜炎
Conjunctivitis.
谁先来
Anyone?
不是吧你
Seriously?
怎么  你们粑粑的时候不能思考吗
What, you two can't think and poop at the same time?
病人可是危在旦夕啊
There's a life at stake here!
会是家族性地中海热吗
Uh...could be familial mediterranean fever?
不像
Not likely.
那个通常会伴有腹痛或者
That almost always presents with abdominal pain or...
腹泻
diarrhea.
从他的工作判断
Given his job,
加之皮肤和眼睛都有问题
the skin and eye involvement,
更像是系统性真菌感染
it's more likely a systemic fungal infection.
那早就该在血液检查里看出来了
Well, we would have seen it in his blood work.
除非是用来还原
Unless the saline used to recover
和储存组织样本的盐水
and store the tissue samples
在最近的研究里显示
has been shown in recent studies--
去取新的血液和脑脊液样本
Get new blood and csf samples
用甲醛代替盐水
using formaldehyde instead of saline.
给他和他老婆用三重抗真菌治疗
And start him and his wife on triple antifungal therapy.
他老婆
His wife?
如果他真想让她快乐
Well, if he's really trying to keep her happy,
我想他们互换过体液了
I assume they've shared bodily fluids.
我恨你
I hate you.
可能是因为你的工作而感染的
You could have picked it up from your job.
真工作  不是假的那个
The...real one, not the fake one.
如果你早点说实话
If you had been more honest about--
那有什么联系
How is that relevant?
如果她妻子知道他的工作
If his wife knew about his job,
他们可能会
they both might have been more alert
对早期症状更加警觉些
to the early symptoms.
我们也能早下手治疗
We could have caught it earlier.
荒谬
That's ridiculous.
天啊  宝贝  真对不起
My god, sweetheart, I'm so sorry.
不管你们在做什么  很显然都没用
Whatever you're doing, it's obviously not working.
我们认为他是系统性真菌感染
We think he has a systemic fungal infection.
我们开始给他用肠胃外抗菌疗法
We're starting him on a parenteral antifungal regimen.
这病可以通过体液传染
It can be transferred through bodily fluids,
所以也准备给你做同样的治疗
so we have to start you on the treatment as well.
真菌  他从哪儿
A fungus? Where would he--
真菌处处存在
It could be from anywhere.
孢子可以通过空气传播
The spores can become airborne.
但怎么就他一个人得了呢
But why would he be the only one?
我们邻居都没有
No one in our neighborhood,
他的同事也没有
no one in his office building?
有时候就是...这样的
Sometimes it just happens...that way.
很难解释
It's hard to explain.
不  不难解释
No. It's not.
我要和我妻子单独谈谈
I need to talk to my wife in private for a moment.
你的检查结果表明药物治疗
Your numbers indicate the medication
对降低你的胆固醇无效
isn't helping with your cholesterol.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你看我是在干什么
What's it look like I'm doing?
为周五的晚会面试乐队呢
Auditioning a band for Friday night.
意思是你要在大庭广众之下
So you're trying to ruin Cuddy's moment
毁掉卡迪的晚会
in the spotlight.
毁掉  这些人给胡安·加布里埃尔伴奏过
Ruin? These guys recorded with Juan Gabriel.
要花我两千大洋呢
They're gonna cost me 2 grand.
这可不是恶作剧
This is not a prank.
他们将会成为
These guys are the beginning
卡迪难忘之夜的开场戏
of Cuddy's evening to remember.
作为回报  她会让我的夜晚...
Which, in turn, will make my evening--
我认为  如果你这么做了
I think, if you do this,
你的夜晚将会在你自己的公寓里
your evening will end with you in your apartment
跟一只臭袜子  孤独得度过
alone...with a sock.
小伙子们  再来一遍[西班牙语]
Muchachos, Adelante.
三  四
Tres, cuatro...
这是最好的结果
This is all for the best.
是啊
Yeah.
要么最好  要么最糟
Either that or... the opposite.
如果你在意的话
If it means anything, um...
我想他真的只是想保护你
I think he's honestly just trying to protect you
让你高兴而已
and keep you happy.
当然  他得在告诉一堆陌生人之后
Oh, God, of course he would tell a bunch of strangers
才肯告诉我
before he would tell me.
为什么不呢  我只是个愚蠢的家庭主妇
I mean, why not? I'm just a stupid housewife, right?
有些事你可以告诉他
You know, I have something you can share with him.
我们结束了
It's over.
他是个骗子  我再也不想见他了
He's a liar, and I never want to hear from him again.
你们去看看他吧  他又发烧了
You may wanna go check on him. His fever's back.
但我再也不会担心他了
But I am done worrying about him.
她没说错  他高烧38度多
She's right. He's at 101.
黛安
Diane?
我们要给你退烧
We're gonna have to get your fever down.
怎  怎么了  你们在说什么
What--what's wrong? What are you saying?
我听不到
I can't hear you.
我  我什么都听不到了
I can't-- I can't hear anything!
为什么我什么都听不到
Why can't I hear anything?
他的听觉几乎完全丧失了
His hearing's almost completely gone.
新的血液和脑脊液检测
The new blood and CSF tests
孢子和真菌都呈阴性
were negative for spores and fungus.
难道是肿瘤坏死因子综合征?
Tumor Necrosis Factor Syndrome?
会出现结膜炎和关节肿大疼痛
Fits the conjunctivitis and painful swelling in his joints.
但从没有记录
Except it's never been documented
会引起听觉丧失  从没
to cause hearing loss. Ever.
不  她不是吧
Oh, no, she di'int!
这不是课堂  这是真实世界
This isn't the classroom. In the real world,
真正的医生知道病人可以
real doctors know that patients can have
同时患有多种病
more than one thing wrong with them.
-没错  -他在用维可丁
- Zing.  - He was taking vicodin.
极度过量滥用会造成听力丧失
Extreme abusers can experience hearing loss.
除了他的用药浓度还没到耳毒水平
Except his drug levels never got into the ototoxic zone.
你有更好的想法吗
You have a better idea?
我有
I do.
只是知道你们俩不过是
Only in the sense that you're wasting my time
五十步笑百步而已  都在浪费时间
with a bad idea and she's wasting my time with no idea.
或许我们该听听沉默者和更沉默者的意见
Maybe we should hear from silent and silenter.
可能是神经性的
It's probably neurological.
脑瘤
Brain tumor?
或者病毒感染到了他的大脑
Or a viral infection that's reached his brain.
我看我们这把听厄尼的
I say we go with Ernie on this one.
做核磁共振  找出来
Get an MRI. Find it.
我准备下周搬出去
I'm gonna move out next week.
做朋友比做室友强
I'd rather stay friends than be roommates.
记得把钥匙还我就行
Just make sure I get my keys back.
又不是我的错
It's not my fault.
我完全煮熟了的
I cooked it thoroughly!
很期待周五晚上吧
Looking forward to Friday night?
是也不是
Yes and no.
是  因为真的是个殊荣
Yes, because it is a great honor,
不是  因为
and no because...
原因你懂的
Well, you know the because.
你觉得豪斯会让你丢脸
You think House is going to embarrass you.
可能不是有意的
Well, not intentionally.
-也可能是有意的  -我知道你的意思
- Maybe intentionally.  - I know what you mean.
我能想象他会干出些啥傻事来  比如
I picture him doing something stupid like...
请个墨西哥流浪乐队什么的
hiring a Mariachi band or something.
实际上  这倒还能接受
Well, actually, I could get behind that.
我去年就想请一个
I tried to hire one last year,
但董事会不让
but the board wouldn't let me
因为他们觉得太贵了
because they thought it was too expensive.
我好冷
I'm freezing.
黛安回来了吗
Is--is Diane coming back?
临床第一课  当病人快死的时候
Bedside 101-- when a patient is near death,
对他们好点
try to be nice.
她不会回来了  我不会骗他的
She's not coming back. I'm not gonna lie to him.
住口
Stop.
什么  你听到她说的话了
What? --You heard what she said.
他在抽搐  得把他弄出来
He's seizing. We gotta get him out of there.
他两个肾都被烤熟了
Both his kidneys are fried.
他正处于昏迷状态
He's in a coma.
可能只剩几天了
He has maybe a few days left.
我们可以试试把他放到器官移植名单上
We can try and get him on the transplant list,
但就他现在的情况  又没有确诊
but in his condition and without a diagnosis,
我想他不会被选上的
I don't see him getting selected.
他也撑不下来手术的
He wouldn't survive the surgery.
符合我刚才的结论
Hence my previous comment.
你希望我们怎么做  豪斯
What do you want us to do, House?
如果是肿瘤  给他做化疗
If it's a tumor, we start chemo.
用射线轰他的脑袋
Bombard his head with radiation.
在这个状态下  可能会害死他
Which will probably kill him in this state.
而且没做核磁共振
And without an MRI,
我们都不确定他是不是有肿瘤
we don't even know if he has one.
但我们什么都不做他肯定会死
He's definitely dead if we do nothing.
如果我错了
If I'm wrong,
我们做的也只是让他早超生几个小时而已
all we do is shave a few hours off.
我们需要他妻子的同意
We'll need his wife's consent.
马斯特斯会搞定的
Masters will get it.
恐怕不是个好主意
Probably not a good idea.
-他说得对  -他说得不对
- Uh, he's right. - No, he's not.
把这当作我正式放你出巢单飞
Consider this me officially booting you out of the nest.
只是来看戏的
Just wanted to watch.
你喜欢我这人吗
Do you even like me?
咋了
Why?
我一直把恋爱交友搁置一旁
I put making friends and having relationships on hold
就为了能一心扑在学业上
so I could concentrate on studying.
我总觉得
I always thought
将来交朋友的时间多得是
there'll be plenty of time for that in the future.
可是
But...
现在我真想跟人交往了
Now when I do want them...
却连个去慈善晚会的伴都找不到
I can't even get a date to this charity event.
如果我和身边的人都没法融洽相处
If I can't establish relationships in my personal life,
还怎么跟病人相处呢
how will I ever do it with a patient?
跟她说实话
Be honest with her.
但在残酷的事实
But if it comes down to a choice
和希望之间
between the brutal truth and hope,
给她希望
side with hope.
他还在昏迷中
He's in a coma.
我们认为是脑瘤
We think it's a brain tumor,
需要你的同意才能开始治疗
and we need your permission to start treatment.
鉴于他目前的状况  治疗的风险
Due to his current condition, the risk factor...
你是说  他可能会死
You mean... it could kill him?
有这种可能
It's possible.
但  还是有希望的
But...there is still hope.
他能听到我说话吗
Can he hear me?
据说昏迷中的人也能听到
They say that that people in comas can still do that.
有时候是  但是你丈夫的听觉
Sometimes, but your husband's hearing...
是可以的
is fine.
我说的那些刻薄话都不是真心的
I didn't mean any of those awful things I said.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
我爱你  伯特
I love you, Bert.
我一直都爱着你
I've always loved you.
我也有一件事瞒着你
I also kept a secret from you.
本来打算在餐馆告诉你的
I was gonna tell you at the restaurant.
可你突然病了
But you got sick.
我本想等你好起来再说的
And I wanted to wait until you felt better.
我怀孕了  亲爱的
I'm pregnant, sweetheart.
你要当爸爸了
You're gonna be a daddy.
为什么再次出现皮疹
Why rash again?
上次退了
It went away.
再次出现必有缘故
It needs a reason to come back.
已经确定不是过敏反应
We know it's not an allergic reaction,
所以一定是我们做了什么诱发的
so we must have done something to set it off again.
是什么呢
What?
-是给他透析吗  -转移到重症病房呢
- We put him on dialysis? - Moved him to the ICU?
还做了一会核磁共振
We also did a partial MRI.
那是皮疹出现两小时前
Two hours before the rash came back.
这两件事没有关联
They're not connected.
他上次发病前
What was he doing
两小时在做什么
two hours before he broke out the first time?
清理犯罪现场
Cleaning a crime scene.
犯罪现场与核磁共振
Crime scene and an MRI.
还是看不出联系
Still not seeing the connection.
整个病例诊断中我们都没能找到联系
We've been missing connections this entire case.
他有说过什么吗
Did he say anything?
他在核磁共振室里有没有表现出不适
Did he show any signs of stress in the MRI room?
他说他冷
He said he was cold,
可那里面一直挺冷的
but it's always freezing in there.
冷和皮疹
Cold and rash.
寒冷性荨麻疹会导致皮疹
Cold urticaria causes rash,
但应该是立即出现  不会延期发作
but it's almost instantaneous and not time-delayed.
而且无法解释他的其他症状
And it wouldn't explain his other symptoms.
这就是我们做了的
That's what we did.
我们给他降温来着
We made him cold.
家族性冷凝荨麻疹
CAPS.
冷凝比邻突变导致的
Genetic disorder caused by a mutation in the cold-induced
遗传性疾病
autoinflammatory syndrome one gene.
毛疴魏症
Muckle-Wells syndrome?
全美也仅有几千例
There's only been a couple thousand
病例记录在案而已
documented cases in the U.S.
那这就是第几千零一例了
Well, now there's a couple thousand and one.
所有症状都吻合
Fits every symptom there.
我们之前居然没看出来真是白痴
We're idiots for not seeing it before.
用利纳西普治疗
Treat with rilonacept.
他会健康长寿的生活在
He'll live a long and healthy life
对他妻子和未来孩子的谎言中
filled with lies to his wife and future child.
你还好吧
You okay?
为什么会不好
Why wouldn't I be?
病例诊断出来了
Solved my case.
可你的病人死了
But your patient died.
我没说是及时诊断
I didn't say in time.
在所难免
It happens.
我救不了所有人
I can't save everyone.
我是来道歉的
I just came to apologize.
你说得没错
You're right.
我内心的确在变得易怒刻薄
I am turning bitter and cynical inside.
你终于要放下那只猫了
You're finally putting the cat down.
她喜欢墨西哥街头乐队  我说过的
She loves Mariachi. I told you.
回家换套行头
Go home and...change.
派对几小时后就开始了
Party's in a few hours.
你不用非得搬走
You don't have to move out
要是你不想搬的话
if you don't want to.
我意识到你说的有一定道理
I realize you might have had a point.
我一个人太久了
I've been alone a long time.
我不想最后混得跟豪斯一样
And I don't want to end up like House.
你说的关于我和我婚姻的那些话
What you said about me and my marriage was...
-都是混账话  -没错
- I was being an ass. - True.
但你说的是事实
But you were right.
我需要有人警醒我
I needed to hear it.
还是兄弟
So we're good.
我这有两张票
You know, I have a couple tickets...
适可而止
Don't push it.
陶博和福曼完事了吗  我要搭他们的车
Taub and Foreman done? I'm hitching a ride with them.
我也是
Me too.
你不去接你的女伴了吗
You're not picking up your date?
没有  我一个人参加
Naw. Going solo.
那些无意义的交往
All those meaningless relationships
时间一长也会让人疲倦的
tend to wear a guy out after a while.
不想错过豪斯的墨西哥街头乐队进场之后
We've got 15 minutes to get there
董事会集体崩溃之盛况的少年们
if we wanna see the board freak
我们还剩十五分钟赶到现场了
when House's Mariachi band marches in.
他们都走了  威尔森
All of them are gone, Wilson.
全部死于我的失误
They're all dead because I am screwed up.
你失去了一个病人
You lost one patient.
而且不是你的错
And it wasn't your fault.
那个把癌症遗传给婴儿的母亲怎么说
What about that mom who gave her baby cancer?
要是我能早些想出病因
If I'd figured that one out quicker,
她现在还活着当妈呢
she'd still be a mom alive.
是她自己拒绝接受治疗的
She refused treatment when it was offered.
这怎么能说是你的错
How is that your fault?
上次全院隔离
And there was that guy I spent a day
和我困在一起一天的那个人
trapped in isolation with.
他就离我一米多远
He was five feet away the whole time.
我却只能像个傻子眼睁睁看着他死去
Just watched him die like an idiot.
是的  你以前失去过病人
Yeah. You've lost patients before,
以后还会再有
and you'll lose patients again.
没错  为什么呢
Exactly! Why?
因为爱与幸福别无益处
Because love and happiness are...
只能让我分心
nothing but distractions.
和卡迪交往让我成了
The only thing my relationship with Cuddy has done for me
糟糕的医生
is make me a worse doctor.
太对了  伟大的豪斯医生不配得到幸福
Right. The great Dr. House doesn't deserve to be happy.
你心里知道不是这样的
You know it's not true.
我的幸福是以别人的生命为代价得来的
My happiness is being paid for by other people's lives.
她怎么样
How is she?
她很担心
She's worried.
你今晚没去她有些不安
She's upset that you didn't show up tonight.
威尔森  我得跟她实话实说
I gotta tell her the truth, Wilson.
首先  首先
First...first,
你甭想开车
you're not driving anywhere.
其次
And second,
你绝对不能这样去找卡迪谈话
you are definitely not talking to Cuddy like this.
好吧
Okay.
我走着去
I'm gonna walk.
我们真的真的需要谈谈
We really, really need to talk.
你醉了  而且你今天彻底搞砸了
You're drunk. And you screwed up big time.
回家去
Go home!
你不但放我鸽子还完全不理我
You completely disappeared on me.
连手机都不接
You wouldn't even answer your cell phone.
你还是坐下听我说吧
You're gonna want to... sit down for this.
去呀
Go ahead.
坐坐坐坐坐
Sit, sit, sit, sit, sit.
我做了个决定
I've made a decision.
爱上你  和你幸福地在一起
Being happy and being in love with you...
让我成了一个糟糕的医生
makes me a crappy doctor.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你醉了  现在谈分手不是时候
You're too drunk to end this relationship.
我是醉了
I am drunk.
可我也是对的
And I'm also right.
你让我变成了一个差劲的医生
You have made me a worse doctor.
这样下去很多人会因此而死的
And people are gonna die because of that.
而且
And...
为了你
you...
这些都是值得的
are totally worth it.
如果救活所有人
If I had to choose between...
与幸福地爱你
saving everyone
二者只能选其一
and loving you and being happy...
我选择你
I choose you.
我选择幸福地跟你在一起
I choose being happy with you.
我永远都会选你
I will always choose you.
我枕在你小妹妹上了
My head's on your vagina.
睡吧  豪斯
Go to sleep, House.
是啊  我是有点儿累了
Yeah. I am kinda tired.